在本节中，我们将讨论不同类型的空间图像处理
In this section we are going to look at a different type of spatial image processing
操作。为了说明这一点，我将采取蒙娜丽莎的形象，我选择了
operation. To illustrate this I am going to take the Mona Lisa image and I have chosen
图像中有大量的随机像素，我将它们设置为0或1。
a large number of random pixels within the image and I have set them to either 0 or 1.
这有时被称为散斑噪声或盐和胡椒噪声。图像现在已损坏;
This is sometimes called speckle noise or salt and pepper noise. The image now is corrupted;
它上面有大量的白色和黑色斑点。
it has got a large number of white and black spots on it.
尝试降低这种噪音影响的一种方法是计算平均值。我们有
One way to try and reduce the effect of this noise would be to compute an average. We have
之前看到平均操作如何趋于模糊并减少精细细节，所以如果
seen before how the averaging operation tends to blur out and reduce fine detail, so if
我计算了这个噪声损坏图像的平均值，我们可以看到这些图像的强度
I compute the average of this noise-corrupted image we can see that the intensity of these
噪声像素已经减少了，但它们也趋向于变得更大。他们有
noise pixels has got less, but they have also tended to get a little bit bigger. They have
被涂抹了，它们现在变得更宽，但它们与背景不同。
been smeared out, they are now wider, but they are not as distinct from the background.
如果我增加用于平均的内核的大小，我们可以看到盐
If I increase the size of the kernel that we use for averaging we can see that the salt
胡椒噪音或许几乎完全消失了，但也有一些抵押品
and pepper noise has perhaps almost completely disappeared, but there has been some collateral
损坏，现在的图像非常模糊。那么有没有办法减少这种盐
damage, the image now is quite blurry. So is there a way that we can reduce this salt
胡椒噪音没有删除我们想要的图像中的细节？
and pepper noise without removing the fine detail in the image that we want?
事实上，这种技术称为秩过滤，所以要看看它是如何工作的
And indeed there is, the technique called rank filtering, so to look at how this works we
将放大原始图像的一个非常小的3×3补丁，我们看到一些
are going to zoom in on a very small 3 by 3 patch of the original image and we see some
此处的灰度值和它们通常在120到130左右-灰度值
grey level values here and they are typically around 120 to 130 — the grey level values
应该在这个特定的区域-我们看到像素的值为0......这个
that should be at this particular region — and we see that pixel has got a value of 0 … this
是一个噪声像素。如果我们计算此窗口的平均值，
is a noise pixel. If we compute the average over this window,
我们看到它的值为110.现在这个值比其他值略低
we see that it has a value of a 110. Now this value is a bit lower than the other values
在这附近;我们可能不会期望这里的值为110。
that are around here; we probably wouldn’t be expecting a value of a 110 here.
而发生的事情是这个0值远离应该的值
And what has happened is that this value of 0 is so far away from the values that should
在这里它已经拉低了平均值，它影响了平均值。
be here that it has pulled the average down, it’s influenced the average.
我们想要一种不同的统计量，实际上就像中值这样的统计量
We want a different sort of statistic, and a statistic like the median value is actually
更有帮助。因此，这个3乘3中位数的中值将是123，那就是
more helpful. So the median value across this 3 by 3 median would be a 123 and that would
或许可以更好地猜测该位置的值应该是多少。我们怎么样
perhaps be a much better guess at what the value should be at this location. How do we
计算中位数？那么计算中位数的最简单方法就是采用所有的方法
compute the median? Well the simplest way to compute the median is to take all of the
在这个3乘3的窗口内的值，并将它们从最大到最小堆叠起来。
values within this 3 by 3 window and stack them up from the largest through to the smallest.
我们将对它们进行排名，排名第1像素是此窗口中的最大值。
We are going to rank them and rank number 1 pixel is the maximum value within this window.
等级9是此窗口中的最小值。等级5是中值和
Rank 9, is the minimum value within this window. And rank 5 is the median value and
它是我们感兴趣的中值。所以让我们将中值滤波器应用于Mona
it is the median value we are interested in. So let’s apply a median filter to the Mona
丽莎形象。在那里，她有盐和胡椒的声音，在这里她就是我们拥有的
Lisa image. There she is with the salt and pepper noise and here she is after we have
使用3乘3中值滤波器-我们可以看到噪声的影响是显着的
applied a 3 by 3 median filter — we can see that the effect of the noise has been dramatically
减少了，但图像中的细节大部分都保留了下来。
reduced, but the fine detail in the image has been mostly retained.
为了计算这个，我们使用工具箱函数irank。第一个参数是输入图像。
To compute this we use the tool box function irank. First argument is the input image.
这种情况下蒙娜丽莎会被噪音破坏，第二个参数是3乘3矩阵
This case it would be noise corrupted Mona Lisa, the second argument is a 3 by 3 matrix
其中，表示我们想要计算中位数的区域的大小。
of ones, which indicates the size of the region over which we want to compute the median.
最后一个参数5是我们想要选择的等级。因为我们已经要求了
And the last argument 5 is the rank that we want to choose. Because we have asked for
中位数超过3乘3的窗口，等级5是其中九个要素的中间值
median over a 3 by 3 window, rank 5 is the middle value of the nine elements within that
窗口。
window.